<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intune on Home</title>
    <link>https://euc365.com/categories/intune/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Intune on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Design By [EUC365](https://euc365.com/) Hosted By [GitHub](https://github.com/)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 08:06:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://euc365.com/categories/intune/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Autopilot Enrolment Terms of Use</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/autopilot-enrolment-terms-of-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 08:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/autopilot-enrolment-terms-of-use/</guid>
      <description>Why would I want to do this? Whats the Purpose? You maybe asking yourself why should I be adding Terms of use to Autopilot Enrolment? Well there are a few use cases that spring to mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Dynamic Application Packages with PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/create-dynamic-application-packages-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 03:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/create-dynamic-application-packages-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>Dynamic? In what way? When I say the packages are dynamic, I mean that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to update the application package when a new version is released by the vendor.
There are caveats to both methods that we walk through below, there are also other community and paid for tools to do similar things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Windows Subsystem for Linux</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/deploy-windows-subsystem-for-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 22:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/deploy-windows-subsystem-for-linux/</guid>
      <description>What is the Windows Susbsystem for Linux? As per the Microsoft Documentation , The Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL) is a new Windows 10 feature that enables you to run native Linux command-line tools directly on Windows, alongside your traditional Windows desktop and modern store apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Intune Win32 Apps</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/creating-intune-win32-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 20:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/creating-intune-win32-apps/</guid>
      <description>Win32 Apps, What Are they? If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with Configuration Manager/MEMCM then think of these files as your source directory, the difference being you are effectively zipping it up and then uploading to Intune.
According to Microsoft, if you decide to use Win32 Apps, it is advised that you use these exclusively and NOT &amp;lsquo;Mix and Match&amp;rsquo; these with Line of Business applications when using Autopilot (See Microsoft Doc link below).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Microsoft Graph API&#39;s from the Web</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/finding-microsoft-graph-apis-from-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 16:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/finding-microsoft-graph-apis-from-the-web/</guid>
      <description>Why do I need to find these? Welcome (Back) to another post about the graph API&amp;rsquo;s, This time it isn&amp;rsquo;t so much about rambling through documentation but about giving you a nice handy tip on your route to finding what API is been called when browsing in the Web Console.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup and Import App Protection Policies</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/backup-and-import-app-protection-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 08:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/backup-and-import-app-protection-policies/</guid>
      <description>Why backup App Protection Policies? Why would you need to back up something that runs in stored and hosted on Azure? Well there are numerous answers to this question really.
 If you make a change and you break something you can look back and analyse what it was You can make copies of the policy easily rather than having two windows side by side In case one is deleted… (Let’s hope this is never the case) To review the maturity of your policies (Lets say you started from ground zero and now have over 100 policy settings… Might be nice to review what you’ve done)  We also live in a world of change management and service improvement so there is always a need to make changes to policies and configurations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup and Import Conditional Access Policies</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/backup-and-import-conditional-access-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 13:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/backup-and-import-conditional-access-policies/</guid>
      <description>Why backup Conditional Access Policies? Why would you need to back up something that runs in stored and hosted on Azure? Well there are numerous answers to this question really.
 If you make a change and you break something you can look back and analyse what it was You can make copies of the policy easily rather than having two windows side by side In case one is deleted… (Let’s hope this is never the case) To review the maturity of your policies (Lets say you started from ground zero and now have over 100 policy settings… Might be nice to review what you’ve done)  We also live in a world of change management and service improvement so there is always a need to make changes to policies and configurations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup and Import Intune Compliance Policies</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/backup-and-import-intune-compliance-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 16:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/backup-and-import-intune-compliance-policies/</guid>
      <description>Why backup Compliance Policies Why would you need to back up something that runs in stored and hosted on Azure? Well there are numerous answers to this question really.
 If you make a change and you break something you can look back and analyse what it was You can make copies of the policy easily rather than having two windows side by side In case one is deleted… (Let’s hope this is never the case) To review the maturity of your policies (Lets say you started from ground zero and now have over 100 policy settings… Might be nice to review what you’ve done)  We also live in a world of change management and service improvement so there is always a need to make changes to policies and configurations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup and Import Intune Device Configuration Profiles</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/backup-and-import-intune-device-configuration-profiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/backup-and-import-intune-device-configuration-profiles/</guid>
      <description>Why backup Device Configuration Profiles? Why would you need to back up something that runs in stored and hosted on Azure? Well there are numerous answers to this question really.
 If you make a change and you break something you can look back and analyse what it was You can make copies of the policy easily rather than having two windows side by side In case one is deleted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add devices to an Azure AD Group using the Microsoft Graph API</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/add-devices-to-an-azure-ad-group-using-the-microsoft-graph-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 11:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/add-devices-to-an-azure-ad-group-using-the-microsoft-graph-api/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever needed to add a device to an Azure AD Group as part of your MEMCM or Autopilot deployment for specific app, profiles or scripts?
Well it became the case that my organisation needed to do so for a couple of reason, one of those was to disable Windows Hello and the other for devices migrating from a previous Configuration Manager (Not MEMCM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enrol Devices to Autopilot (Unattended)</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/enrol-devices-to-autopilot-unattended/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/enrol-devices-to-autopilot-unattended/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on a project at the company I work for, and up to this point we have been primarily focused on getting new devices imported and deploying via Autopilot.
Now we have successfully leaped over that hurdle with very little issues (apart from the odd TPM attestation issue here and there and the ESP Profile page been skipped), we moved onto focusing on our current estate and how to import these into Autopilot .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Down Custom OMA-URI (CSP) Policies</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/breaking-down-custom-oma-uri-csp-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 18:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/breaking-down-custom-oma-uri-csp-policies/</guid>
      <description>What is an OMA-URI Policy? Meaning: Open Mobile Alliance Uniform Resource Identifier Traditionally when you implement a new piece of software which contains Group Policy Objects (GPO&amp;rsquo;s) to customise the feature of the application you would import the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Useful Device Information… Troubleshooting Made Easy</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/getting-useful-device-information-troubleshooting-made-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/getting-useful-device-information-troubleshooting-made-easy/</guid>
      <description>SO&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve been working tirelessly in trying to get an Autopilot Hybrid Deployment working along with my colleagues. As any Tech does I give everything my blood sweat and tears before logging a call with support (Sound silly as we could waste hours&amp;hellip; But where&amp;rsquo;s the fun in just logging a call), however on occasion you have to admit defeat and raise a service request.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
