<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud PC on EUC365 | Modern Technology Blog</title>
    <link>https://euc365.com/tags/cloud-pc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud PC on EUC365 | Modern Technology Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 09:16:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://euc365.com/tags/cloud-pc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Create Windows 365 Azure Network Connections with PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/post/create-windows-365-azure-network-connections-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 09:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/post/create-windows-365-azure-network-connections-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Windows 365 and Azure Network connections offers additional control over routing, IP Addresses, Subnets, Peerings and so on. It can also be incredibly useful to help with testing moving to Azure AD Only (Can you tell, I&amp;rsquo;m already not a fan of HAADJ), as with the right configuration on your Azure vNet you can connect back to your internal network and get straight to testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using an ANC with Windows 365 and Cloud PCs does bring an additional cost, not to the license or compute though, just the network usage cost. Microsoft do recommend using their Hosted Network, but they are not fools, they have built a system for enterprise and allowing the capability of Bring-Your-Own-Network (BYON) is a clear no brainer for organisations with existing on-premise infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BYON doesn&amp;rsquo;t just have to be used for a gateway connection back to on-premise though, it can be used to just add more control over the network traffic on these endpoint with firewalls etc. There is some further documentation on Azure Network Connections over on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-365/enterprise/azure-network-connections&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Learn Page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this post, I wanted to explore creating these connections with PowerShell and the Graph API. We will explore both Azure AD Only and Hybrid Joined ANCs and the differences in the policy creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/cloud-adoption-framework/ready/landing-zone/design-area/resource-org-subscriptions&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Azure Subscription&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/virtual-network/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Azure Virtual Network (vNet)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Owner Permissions on the Subscription where the Network Resides&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be an Intune Administrator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hybrid-azure-ad-join&#34;&gt;Hybrid Azure AD Join&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the chosen deployment option is HAADJ, you will need to ensure the network has line of sight to your domain controllers and that DNS can be resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the above, you will require a domain &lt;strong&gt;Service Account&lt;/strong&gt; which can join devices to the domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-the-policies&#34;&gt;Creating the Policies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;notices warning&#34; &gt;&lt;p&gt;You may need to grant permissions to the PowerShell module within your Tenant. If this is the case and you do not have access to grant the relevant permissions, please reach out to an administrator who can grant these rights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both instances, there are details we require for the creation of the connection so lets grab them first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SubscriptionID&lt;/strong&gt; - The Subscription ID in which the Virtual Network Resides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resource Group Name&lt;/strong&gt; - The name of the resource group where the Virtual Network resides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Virtual Network Name&lt;/strong&gt; - The name of the Virtual Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vNet Subnet Name&lt;/strong&gt; - The name of the Subnet which resides within the vNet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the above, for Hybrid machines you will also require the following;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Domain Join Service Account&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OU Path&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Domain DNS Suffix&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g euc365.lab)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;notices tip&#34; &gt;&lt;p&gt;As noted in the prerequisites, ensure you have Owner rights at the time of creation on the Subscription.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scripts quoted in this article, are available on GitHub, please use the link below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/brookd2404/windows365/tree/main/Azure%20Network%20Connections/Creation&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://euc365.com/images/git_resource.png&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub Resource&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, lets look at creating a &lt;strong&gt;NON&lt;/strong&gt; Hybrid connection. If you download the files from the GitHub Repo, this will be the &lt;strong&gt;create-w365-ANC-aad.ps1&lt;/strong&gt; script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you open it up and take a look inside, you can see, there is no major magic that is happening inside, it is just taking out passed in variables and building up the &lt;code&gt;$params&lt;/code&gt; variable, which will be used as the body of our Graph Call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the call is made, Windows 365 then runs checks on the Network connection to make sure everything is good to run machines from, for that reason you can not know for sure if it will work straight away, which is why at the end their is a &lt;strong&gt;DO, WHILE loop&lt;/strong&gt; to ensure we know the final outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tests can vary in the amount of time taken to complete, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen one take more than 10 Minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we look at how we can then execute this script using the command line, we would use the following command with the placeholders replaced with their representational values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;create-w365-ANC-aad.ps1 -subscription &amp;lt;SubscriptionID&amp;gt; -resourceGroupName &amp;lt;RGName&amp;gt; -vNetName &amp;lt;vNetName&amp;gt; -subnetName &amp;lt;subnetName&amp;gt; -ancName &amp;lt;ancName&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once executed, you will see the following in the shell window.&lt;/p&gt;

















&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; class=&#34;mx-auto d-block&#34; src=&#34;https://euc365.com/images/post/w365/ancCreatinonPSaad_hufbb491b713e446a3d71236753c81606d_24617_750x0_resize_q100_h2_box_3.webp&#34; alt=&#34;AAD Creation&#34; height=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;&#34;&gt;



&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Network connection will also be available in the Windows 365 blade within Intune.&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; class=&#34;mx-auto d-block&#34; src=&#34;https://euc365.com/images/post/w365/ancFeature_hu9332d07731226b04fa6e5eb784787c2b_18764_509x0_resize_q100_h2_box_3.webp&#34; alt=&#34;ANC Created&#34; height=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;&#34;&gt;



&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if we take a look at the HAADJ Scenario, there are a few more variables required which are, &lt;code&gt;$domainOU&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;$domainDNSSuffix&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;$domainJoinUser&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;$domainJoinUserPWD&lt;/code&gt;. The  &lt;code&gt;$domainOU&lt;/code&gt; variable must be populated with the distinguished name of the OU, for example OU=Devices,DC=EUC365,DC=LAB and the &lt;code&gt;$domainJoinUser&lt;/code&gt; must be the user principal name, for example **&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:joiner@euc365.lab&#34;&gt;joiner@euc365.lab&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;notices warning&#34; &gt;&lt;p&gt;The password will be plain text.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We execute this script in the same way as the above with the additional cmdlets as shown below with the additional placeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;create-w365-ANC-haadk.ps1 -subscription &amp;lt;SubscriptionID&amp;gt; -resourceGroupName &amp;lt;RGName&amp;gt; -vNetName &amp;lt;vNetName&amp;gt; -subnetName &amp;lt;subnetName&amp;gt; -ancName &amp;lt;ancName&amp;gt; -domainOU &amp;lt;e.g OU=Devices,DC=EUC365,DC=LAB&amp;gt; -domainDNSSuffix &amp;lt;e.g euc365.lab&amp;gt; -domainJoinUser &amp;lt;e.g Joiner@euc365.lab&amp;gt; -domainJoinUserPWD &amp;quot;iamplaintext&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The platform will then again perform the relevant checks to ensure it can connect to the domain, look up DNS etc, so please ensure your vNet and subnet are configured accordingly for this test to pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is only one piece of the puzzle, but what I would say, is if you do not need one for a certain purpose (i.e routing back to on-premise) do not create one. It adds another level of management and complexity where it is not required, and if you use the moto of less is more, then you can save the management in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please leave comments and reactions below, and let me know your experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Windows 365?</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/post/why-windows-365/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 11:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/post/why-windows-365/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Windows 365 (Cloud PC) is the hot topic of the moment, and why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be? For many years, before most can remember, it has been the norm for IT Departments to Image, configure and deploy Laptops and Workstations for end-users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, over the past couple of years, with COVID and other factors, the world has moved to a more distributed workforce, where country boundaries are no longer the border of employment. Companies invested in further development on  their virtualisation offerings, such as Azure Virtual Desktop, VMWare Horizon, Citrix etc., however, all of these solutions require specialised skill sets and are very complex and often high maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft&lt;/strong&gt; has taken this one step further and created a PaaS (Platform as a Service) solution that integrates and is managed via Microsoft Intune, delivering the &lt;strong&gt;&amp;lsquo;Single Pane of Glass&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt; management that many businesses seek. The beauty of this is that you do not need to maintain complex infrastructure and configuration sets or perform platform upgrades (including hardware replacements).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As demonstrated in my VLOG post &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7maeZJaturI&amp;amp;t=179s&#34;&gt;Getting Started with Windows 365 Enterprise&lt;/a&gt;, the deployment of a Windows 365 Machine is Quick, Simple and Easy. There are additional components that Windows 365 is capable of using, such as Customer Managed Networks and Custom Images, which add other complexities, but these are optional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt; 
&lt;h2 id=&#34;organisational-advantages-and-use-cases&#34;&gt;Organisational Advantages and Use Cases&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows 365 and Cloud PCs can benefit organisations in many ways, from onboarding users in remote locations to exploring an Azure AD Join strategy without requiring complex setups of multiple physical machines, VMs etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Cloud PCs are subscription-based, it is simple to cancel the subscription, and all the costs for that license will no longer be billed. The user can use the Cloud PC until the end of the license term, and then the platform destroys the machine after a brief grace period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most significant use cases for the platform, is for Temporary Staff (Contractors, Consultancies, short-term employees etc.), as the cost of purchasing additional hardware. If the end-user is in a remote location, it saves on shipping costs and the risk of damage or total loss of the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets look at this scenario. Think of an end-user having an issue with a device whereby the device requires re-provisioning. While this is still a simple task on a well-constructed Modern Implementation of Device Management, an endpoint could be out of action for two or more hours. This also assumes the user does not request additional support. Well, with Cloud PCs, the IT Administrator can re-provision the machine within the Intune UI, and within an hour, the endpoint will be back up and running, ready for the user to be productive once again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe re-provisioning isn&amp;rsquo;t the desired approach to every scenario, so Windows 365 also offers device restore points, which are configurable by administrators, and users can even restore the devices themselves using the WebUI or the Windows 365 Application.&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; class=&#34;mx-auto d-block&#34; src=&#34;https://euc365.com/images/post/w365/CloudPCOptions_hu243cd0fd70bec37d3c1a42130b6b2108_81239_460x0_resize_q100_h2_box_3.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Cloud PC Options&#34; height=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you are using Intune and Autopilot to manage devices, you can also use the same configuration policies (minus BitLocker) to manage these devices, Windows 365 Machines also support the use of ESP Policies, so they can be managed the same way as standard physical endpoints, you can read more on this in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-365/enterprise/enrollment-status-page&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Documentation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the implementation strategy, it can be integrated into your current SLAM (Starters, Leaver and Movers) process with ease. For example, if you have a Microsoft Form that triggers a Flow, you could add a step to add the new account to the Windows 365 Licensed Group that is in the scope of a provisioning policy and the machine creation will trigger and be available in a short space of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many other use cases and benefits to using Windows 365, and this post is to get you started on your journey and get people thinking about &lt;strong&gt;Why Windows 365&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use a Cloud PC to perform all of my developmental activities, this allows me to install all of the software I use without ever worrying about it been on my physical device, that as we all know, can have unexpected issues and sometimes require a reset. It also allows me to separate my workloads and have a more Powerful Cloud PC and a less powerful device if needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;accessibility&#34;&gt;Accessibility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can access Windows 365 from any device, Windows, Mac, iOS/iPadOS, Android and Linux. For example, using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://windows365.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web UI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or OS-specific applications, making the platform readily available to users, no matter where they are or what device they are using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hybrid-join&#34;&gt;Hybrid Join&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I would recommend that this is avoided, there are still use cases where this may be a necessary evil. Windows 365 does support Hybrid Joining clients to the Windows Domain, and all of the information can be found in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-365/enterprise/deployment-options#hybrid-azure-ad-join&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Docuemtnation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cannot rave about Cloud PC and Windows 365 enough, it has really changed how I work. I hope this post has been useful and highlights the reasons to implement and invest in Windows 365 for your organisations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summery-of-benefits&#34;&gt;Summery of Benefits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cost Saving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scalability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ease of Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No need to carry around multiple devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to integrate with current proccess&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No need for an additional policy set&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>