<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure AD on Home</title>
    <link>https://euc365.com/tags/azure-ad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure AD on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Design By [EUC365](https://euc365.com/) Hosted By [GitHub](https://github.com/)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 08:06:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://euc365.com/tags/azure-ad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Autopilot Enrolment Terms of Use</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/autopilot-enrolment-terms-of-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 08:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/autopilot-enrolment-terms-of-use/</guid>
      <description>Why would I want to do this? Whats the Purpose? You maybe asking yourself why should I be adding Terms of use to Autopilot Enrolment? Well there are a few use cases that spring to mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup and Import App Protection Policies</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/backup-and-import-app-protection-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 08:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/backup-and-import-app-protection-policies/</guid>
      <description>Why backup App Protection Policies? Why would you need to back up something that runs in stored and hosted on Azure? Well there are numerous answers to this question really.
 If you make a change and you break something you can look back and analyse what it was You can make copies of the policy easily rather than having two windows side by side In case one is deleted… (Let’s hope this is never the case) To review the maturity of your policies (Lets say you started from ground zero and now have over 100 policy settings… Might be nice to review what you’ve done)  We also live in a world of change management and service improvement so there is always a need to make changes to policies and configurations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup and Import Conditional Access Policies</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/backup-and-import-conditional-access-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 13:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/backup-and-import-conditional-access-policies/</guid>
      <description>Why backup Conditional Access Policies? Why would you need to back up something that runs in stored and hosted on Azure? Well there are numerous answers to this question really.
 If you make a change and you break something you can look back and analyse what it was You can make copies of the policy easily rather than having two windows side by side In case one is deleted… (Let’s hope this is never the case) To review the maturity of your policies (Lets say you started from ground zero and now have over 100 policy settings… Might be nice to review what you’ve done)  We also live in a world of change management and service improvement so there is always a need to make changes to policies and configurations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add devices to an Azure AD Group using the Microsoft Graph API</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/add-devices-to-an-azure-ad-group-using-the-microsoft-graph-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 11:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/add-devices-to-an-azure-ad-group-using-the-microsoft-graph-api/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever needed to add a device to an Azure AD Group as part of your MEMCM or Autopilot deployment for specific app, profiles or scripts?
Well it became the case that my organisation needed to do so for a couple of reason, one of those was to disable Windows Hello and the other for devices migrating from a previous Configuration Manager (Not MEMCM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create an Azure App Registration</title>
      <link>https://euc365.com/create-an-azure-app-registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://euc365.com/create-an-azure-app-registration/</guid>
      <description>What can you use an Azure App Registration for An Azure App Registration has many uses, in my case I use it mainly for the Microsoft Graph API to perform Intune Configuration Profile backups, List devices, Update local CMDB dynamically and also enrol devices into Autopilot.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
